You should've stayed with them, considering how serious the situation is.
‪สถานการณ์แบบนี้ทิ้งภรรยากับลูกไว้ได้ยังไงคะ
Are you sure they're at home?
‪แน่ใจเหรอคะว่าอยู่บ้าน
Listen, Mr. Bae.
‪คุณแบยองแจ ฟังดีๆ นะคะ
The New Truth and the Arrowhead are working together.
‪กลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่กับพวกหัวศรคือฝ่ายเดียวกันค่ะ
The Arrowhead raided my office last night,
‪เมื่อวานฉันถูกพวกหัวศรลอบทำร้าย
and the New Truth deacons were with them.
‪แล้วที่นั่นก็มีนักบวชของกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่
If they find out that your baby received the decree,
‪ถ้าพวกนั้นรู้ว่าลูกคุณได้รับประกาศิต
you and your wife will be in danger.
‪คุณแบยองแจและภรรยาจะไม่ปลอดภัยค่ะ
I'll have to call you back in a minute.
‪อีกเดี๋ยวผมจะโทรไปใหม่นะครับ
YOUNGJAE
‪(คุณยองแจ)
-Ms. Song Sohyun? -Yes?
‪- คุณซงโซฮยอน ‪- คะ
Please come this way.
‪เชิญทางนี้ค่ะ
Your call cannot be connected…
‪ไม่สามารถติดต่อเลขหมายปลายทางได้…
SOHYUN WHERE ARE YOU RIGHT NOW?
‪(โซฮยอน ตอนนี้อยู่ไหน)
YOU DIDN'T GO TO THE NEW TRUTH, DID YOU?
‪(เธอคงไม่ได้ไปหากลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ใช่ไหม)
PLEASE CALL AS SOON AS YOU SEE THIS
‪(เห็นข้อความแล้วโทรมาทันทีนะ)
I'M SORRY, YOUNGJAE
‪(ฉันขอโทษนะ ยองแจ)
I NEED TO ASK THE NEW TRUTH DEACONS WHY OUR BABY RECEIVED THE DECREE
‪(ฉันต้องถามนักบวชกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ให้รู้เรื่อง ‪ว่าทำไมลูกเราถึงได้รับประกาศิต)
Good morning.
‪สวัสดีครับ
I'm Deacon Yuji.
‪ผมนักบวชยูจีครับ
I heard you have something to discuss with me.
‪ได้ยินว่าคุณมีเรื่องจะปรึกษาผม
Please take a look at this.
‪ฉันอยากให้ดูอันนี้หน่อยค่ะ
Ms. Min, my wife said she went to the New Truth.
‪ครับ คุณทนาย ภรรยาผมบอกว่า ‪เธอไปหากลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่แล้ว
You must get your wife and baby out of there.
‪ต้องทำทุกทางเพื่อพาตัวภรรยากับลูกมานะคะ
We'll be there as soon as possible.
‪ทางเราก็จะไปให้เร็วที่สุดค่ะ
Okay.
‪เข้าใจแล้วครับ
Song Sohyun's baby.
‪ลูกน้อยของซงโซฮยอน
In three days…
‪อีกสามวันจากนี้
-at 9:30 p.m.… -Deacon Yuji.
‪- เวลา 21:30 นาฬิกา… ‪- ท่านนักบวช
Has there ever been a mistake in the decree?
‪มีกรณีที่ประกาศิตผิดพลาดด้วยไหมคะ
…you are bound for Hell.
‪เธอจะตกนรก
My baby was just born.
‪ทารกที่เพิ่งเกิดไม่นาน
What sin could my baby have committed?
‪จะก่อบาปได้ยังไงกันคะ
People here study all the cases of demonstrations and decrees.
‪คนที่นี่ศึกษาทุกการสาธิตและประกาศิตนี่คะ
Something has gone wrong, right?
‪มีอะไรผิดพลาดใช่ไหมคะ
Even deacons don't know…
‪ใช่ว่าเป็นนักบวช
about all the cases out there.
‪แล้วจะรู้ทุกกรณีนะครับ
Let us discuss this internally.
‪เราจะขอหารือเรื่องนี้กันภายในนะครับ
Could you please wait a moment?
‪รอสักครู่ได้หรือเปล่าครับ
Okay.
‪ค่ะ
Make sure the woman in Room Four doesn't leave the premises.
‪เฝ้าระวังอย่าให้ผู้หญิงในห้องสี่ ‪ออกไปข้างนอกนะครับ
Yes, sir.
‪ค่ะ
Tell Deacon Sacheong to come in immediately and keep an eye on her.
‪แล้วก็รีบติดต่อท่านนักบวชซาชอง ‪ให้รีบมาที่ห้องและจับตามองเธอไว้ครับ
Yes, sir.
‪ค่ะ รับทราบค่ะ
Chairman Kim, I need you to call an urgent committee meeting.
‪ท่านประธาน ‪เราต้องประชุมคณะกรรมการด่วนครับ
YOUNGJAE
‪(ยองแจ)
Your call cannot be connected…
‪ไม่สามารถติดต่อเลขหมายปลายทางได้…
Song Sohyun's baby.
‪ลูกน้อยของซงโซฮยอน
In three days,
‪อีกสามวันจากนี้
at 9:30 p.m.,
‪เวลา 21:30 นาฬิกา
you are bound for Hell.
‪เธอจะตกนรก
Where are the mother and the baby?
‪ตอนนี้ทารกกับแม่อยู่ไหนนะครับ
They are in a consulting room.
‪อยู่ที่ห้องให้คำปรึกษาครับ
What do you think we should do?
‪คณะกรรมการของเรามีความเห็นว่าไงครับ
Anyone?
‪หือ
It's hard for me to suggest anything right now.
‪สำหรับตอนนี้คงยากที่จะพูดอะไร
But one thing is clear.
‪แต่มีเรื่องหนึ่งที่ชัดเจนค่ะ
That video.
‪คลิปวิดีโอนั่น
If people find out about it,
‪เมื่อวิดีโอนั้นถูกเปิดเผยให้คนรู้
they will start to have doubts about the New Truth and our doctrine.
‪ผู้คนก็จะเริ่มแคลงใจในหลักคำสอน ‪ของกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ค่ะ
You're right.
‪ก็ใช่นะ
First, isolate the baby and the mother separately.
‪ก่อนอื่นแยกทารกกับผู้หญิงออกจากกันครับ
Find out who else knows about the video.
‪แล้วก็ไปสืบมาว่าใครรู้เรื่องในวิดีโอนั้นบ้าง
Bring them to isolation.
‪แล้วกักตัวออกมาให้หมดครับ
Yes, sir.
‪รับทราบครับ
THE NEW TRUTH
‪(กลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่)
GET OUT OF THERE RIGHT NOW!
‪(รีบออกมาจากตรงนั้นซะ)
Where's the mother?
‪แม่เด็กอยู่ไหน
She's in Room Four.
‪ห้องสี่ค่ะ
You're late. Did she get back to you?
‪มาสายนะคะ เธอติดต่อมาหรือยัง
No. I can't get a hold of her.
‪ไม่ครับ ตอนนี้ยังติดต่อไม่ได้
The consulting rooms are in Building B over there.
‪ห้องให้คำปรึกษาตึกบีไปทางนี้ค่ะ
Don't cry, my dear.
‪ไม่ต้องร้องนะ
Don't cry.
‪ไม่ต้องร้อง
Hello, Ms. Song. I'm Deacon Sacheong.
‪คุณซงโซฮยอน สวัสดีครับ ผมนักบวชซาชองครับ
We'd like to give you a detailed explanation on the matter.
‪เราจะมาอธิบาย ‪เกี่ยวกับเรื่องนี้อย่างละเอียดให้ฟัง
Please come with us.
‪ไปกับเราสักครู่นะครับ
Oh, my. The baby's crying so much.
‪โธ่ เด็กร้องใหญ่เลย
-Let me take the baby. -No, there's no need--
‪- ส่งเด็กให้ฉันเถอะค่ะ ‪- ไม่ค่ะ ไม่เป็นไร…
It's okay. I'm good with babies.
‪ไม่เป็นไรค่ะ ฉันเลี้ยงเด็กเก่ง
-Give me the baby. -No, I've got it!
‪- ให้ฉันเถอะ ‪- ไม่ค่ะ ฉันจะอุ้มเอง
Please get your bag and come out.
‪คุณแม่ถือกระเป๋าออกมานะคะ
Excuse me! Give me back my baby!
‪คุณคะ เอาลูกมาให้ฉันค่ะ ส่งลูกให้ฉันค่ะ
Reporters.
‪คุณนักข่าวทั้งหลาย
Chairman Kim has other priorities today,
‪ขณะนี้ท่านประธานกำลังยุ่งมาก
so I'm afraid I have to ask you to leave.
‪วันนี้อยากให้ทุกท่านกลับไปก่อนครับ
We are still looking into Professor Gong's case and the Arrowhead's statement.
‪ทางเรากำลังสืบเรื่องศาสตราจารย์กงฮยองจุน ‪และคำแถลงจากพวกหัวศรก่อนหน้านี้อยู่
We don't have an official statement yet.
‪ยังไม่มีแถลงการณ์อย่างเป็นทางการครับ
The Arrowhead mentioned the New Truth in their statement,
‪กลุ่มหัวศรได้พูดถึงกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ ‪ในคำแถลงการณ์ด้วย
but you are not commenting on it?
‪มาพูดว่าไม่มีแถลงการณ์มันถูกเหรอคะ
The Arrowhead staged a demonstration and punished victims.
‪กลุ่มหัวศรลงโทษคนโดยเลียนแบบการสาธิต
Shouldn't you at least comment on it?
‪คุณควรจะแสดงออกถึงเรื่องนี้หน่อยไหมครับ
We have no plan to comment on any of the issues at the moment.
‪สำหรับตอนนี้เรายังไม่มีแผน ‪ที่จะแสดงความเห็นใดๆ ครับ
I would like to ask you to leave now.
‪วันนี้รบกวนกลับไปก่อนนะครับ
Deacon, are you refusing to comment on the issues?
‪ท่านนักบวช พูดอะไรหน่อยครับ ‪จะไม่แสดงความเห็นใช่ไหมครับ
-Correct. You should leave. -Deacon, give us a comment.
‪- ใช่ครับ กลับไปเถอะครับ ‪- ท่านนักบวช
-Please leave. -Give us a comment.
‪- กลับไปครับ ‪- พูดอะไรหน่อยครับ
Deacon!
‪ท่านนักบวช
I received the decree!
‪ผมได้รับประกาศิตครับ
Who is that?
‪ใครนะ
I'm a sinner who's bound for Hell in ten minutes.
‪ผมคือคนบาปที่จะตกนรกในอีกสิบนาทีครับ
-Take pictures. Follow him. -Who is that?
‪- ถ่ายไว้เร็ว ตามเขาไป ‪- เฮ้ย นั่นใคร
I'd like to confess my sins to the chairman this instant…
‪ผมจะสารภาพบาปต่อท่านประธานตอนนี้ทันที
and face the demonstration.
‪และเผชิญหน้ากับการสาธิตครับ
-Get him! -Right here, right now!
‪- รีบจับเขาไว้ ‪- ตรงนี้เวลานี้
-No, up here! I'll face it up here! -Take him down!
‪- ไม่ ผมจะรับการสาธิตข้างบนนี้ครับ ‪- เอาเขาลงมา
A man is causing a scene in the lobby
‪ชายคนหนึ่งก่อความวุ่นวายที่ล็อบบี้ ‪บอกว่าจะรับการสาธิต
In ten minutes?
‪อีกสิบนาทีเหรอ
I'll go check what's going on. Keep a close eye on the mother.
‪ผมจะไปเช็กสถานการณ์ก่อน ‪ฝากดูแลคุณซงโซฮยอนด้วยครับ
-Yes, sir.
‪- ได้ค่ะ ‪- ได้ครับ
Wait.
‪เดี๋ยวก่อนค่ะ
Give me back my baby.
‪คืนลูกมาให้ฉันเถอะค่ะ
Get her off me!
‪จัดการผู้หญิงคนนี้ค่ะ
What's wrong with you? Give me back my baby!
‪พูดอะไรน่ะ ส่งลูกฉันคืนมานะ
Why are you doing this? My baby! Let go of me!
‪ทำแบบนี้ทำไม ลูกฉัน ปล่อยฉันนะ
Get her out of here!
‪ลากตัวไป
Get your hands off her, you bastard!
‪ปล่อยมือนะ ไอ้พวกเวร
Let go, you son of a--
‪บอกให้ปล่อยไงวะ…
Hey, go get her.
‪เฮ้ย จับตัวมัน
My baby…
‪ลูกฉัน…
Sohyun! Stop!
‪โซฮยอน
You bastard.
‪ไอ้สารเลว
-You arrogant bastard… -Sohyun!
‪- ไอ้… ‪- โซฮยอน
Oh, no!
‪ไม่นะ
Give me back my baby!
‪เอาลูกฉันคืนมา
Get her off me! Come on, stop her!
‪เอาตัวหล่อนไป นี่ หยุดสิ
What are you doing?
‪ทำอะไรคะ
Sohyun!
‪โซฮยอน
Die, you bitch.
‪ตายซะ นังสารเลว
Call security right now!
‪รีบติดต่อรปภ.เดี๋ยวนี้
Hurry!
‪เร็วเข้าค่ะ
Chairman Kim! Please accept this sinner's plea.
‪ท่านประธาน ได้โปรดยอมรับคนบาปคนนี้เถิด
Chairman Kim, where are you?
‪ท่านประธาน ท่านอยู่ไหนครับ
They're coming.
‪มาแล้ว
Drag him out of here right now!
‪รีบลากตัวเขาคนนั้นมาครับ
-Yes, sir. -Yes, sir. Grab him.
‪- ครับ ‪- ครับ จับไว้
I'll drive.
‪ฉันจะขับเองค่ะ
Stop them!
‪จับไว้ จับมันไว้
Stop the car!
‪หยุดรถนะ
Block the entrance!
‪ปิดประตูทางออกเร็วเข้า
Will that man in the lobby be okay?
‪ผู้ชายคนเมื่อกี้จะเป็นอะไรไหมครับ
They can't do anything to him now because of the reporters.
‪พวกเขาคงจะทำอะไรทันทีไม่ได้ ‪เพราะมีนักข่าวอยู่เยอะค่ะ
He'll be under our protection afterwards.
‪หลังจากนี้เราจะคุ้มครองเขาครับ
Chairman…
‪ท่านประธาน…
I promise I'll do whatever it takes to find them.
‪ไม่ว่าจะเกิดอะไรผมจะจับคนพวกนั้น…
What did you say?
‪จะทำยังไงงั้นเหรอ
What?
‪ฮะ
You've got some nerve, carrying on like that after what you've done!
‪นี่ ยังจะทำอะไรอีกในเมื่อเรื่องเป็นแบบนี้แล้ว
You had them, and let them slip right through your hands.
‪คนที่มาให้จับถึงที่ คุณยังทำหลุดมือได้
How are you going to catch them now? Do you have a plan in mind?
‪แล้วจะเอาหน้าที่ไหนไปจับเขาอีก
Say something!
‪พูดออกมาสิ
Do you have any idea what you've done?
‪พวกคุณรู้ตัวบ้างหรือเปล่าว่าก่อเรื่องอะไรไว้
The demonstration is tomorrow.
‪พรุ่งนี้จะถึงการสาธิตอยู่แล้วนะ
What do you think will happen if people find out about it?
‪ถ้าคนรู้เรื่องนั้นเข้า มันจะเกิดอะไรขึ้น
Pandemonium! It'll be the end of the world!
‪โกลาหลครั้งใหญ่ อวสานโลกแน่
They will think God is a joke whose actions are not governed by principles.
‪คนจะคิดว่าการกระทำของพระเจ้า ‪เป็นแค่เรื่องล้อเล่นซึ่งไม่มีหลักการรองรับ
What do you think will happen in a world without principles?
‪คิดว่าโลกที่ไร้หลักการจะเป็นยังไงล่ะ
It will come to an end!
‪ก็อวสานไงเล่า
You are the ones who brought the world to an end.
‪ตอนนี้พวกคุณนำอวสานมาสู่โลกแล้ว
All right.
‪เอาล่ะ
From now on, you must report every little thing to me.
‪หลังจากนี้ ถ้าได้ความอะไร ‪แม้แต่เรื่องเล็กน้อยก็ให้รายงานผม
Make use of the Arrowhead.
‪ใช้ประโยชน์จากพวกหัวศรให้เต็มที่
We need to stop the world from collapsing.
‪เราต้องหยุดยั้งอวสานของโลกไว้สิ
You may leave.
‪ออกไปได้ครับ
CHAIRMAN KIM JEONGCHIL
‪(ประธาน คิมจองชิล)
JEONGDAM GROCERY STORE
‪(ร้านขายผลไม้ชองดัม)
Can we trust this person?
‪คนคนนี้เชื่อใจได้เหรอครับ
One of our members in this area referred me to him.
‪เขาคือคนที่สมาชิกทีมเราที่อยู่แถวนี้แนะนำมา
He received the decree long ago and is waiting for his demonstration.
‪เขาได้รับประกาศิตมานานแล้ว ‪และกำลังรอการสาธิตอยู่ค่ะ
We should stay here for now.
‪เอาเป็นว่าอยู่ที่นี่กันก่อนค่ะ
Hello, Ms. Min. I was surprised to hear you were coming.
‪อ้าว ทนายมิน ผมตกใจแทบแย่ตอนรู้ว่าคุณจะมา
Please come in.
‪เชิญเข้ามาครับ
You've come to such a humble place as this.
‪คุณทนายอุตส่าห์มาในที่โทรมๆ แบบนี้
Please have a seat.
‪นั่งสิครับ
Would you like some coffee?
‪รับกาแฟหน่อยไหมครับ กาแฟ
I have some instant coffee mix.
‪กาแฟสำเร็จรูปนะครับ
-Sounds great. Thank you. -All right. Please have a seat.
‪- ค่ะ ขอบคุณนะคะ ‪- ครับ นั่งเลยครับ
Ms. Song, we only have one day.
‪คุณโซฮยอน ตอนนี้เหลือแค่วันเดียวแล้วนะคะ
Your baby would mean a lot to the countless victims of the New Truth.
‪เด็กคนนี้จะเป็นพลังให้กับเหยื่อ ‪ของกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ที่นับไม่ถ้วนได้มากเลยค่ะ
I regret to suggest something like this,
‪ฉันเสียใจจริงๆ ที่ต้องเสนอแบบนี้
but if you put off making a decision any longer,
‪แต่ถ้ายังยืดเยื้อกว่านี้อีกแค่นิดเดียว
the New Truth could barge in any minute and harm the baby and both of you.
‪พวกสัจธรรมใหม่อาจจะบุกเข้ามา ‪ทำร้ายคุณสองคนและลูกก็ได้ค่ะ
They could commit murder without batting an eyelid.
‪คนพวกนั้นเข่นฆ่าคนได้ไม่เลือกหน้าค่ะ
You have to make a decision now.
‪ตอนนี้ต้องตัดสินใจแล้วนะคะ
Here's your coffee.
‪กาแฟได้แล้วครับ
Poor baby.
‪โธ่ เด็กน้อย
I heard the baby received the decree.
‪ผมได้ยินมาแล้วครับว่าทารกได้รับประกาศิต
How could the baby
‪ทารก
have committed any sins?
‪จะก่อบาปอะไรได้ล่ะครับ
The same goes for me.
‪แล้วผมทำบาปกรรมอะไรไว้ล่ะครับ
I was a follower of the New Truth.
‪ผมเคยเป็นผู้ศรัทธากลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ครับ
I lived by their doctrine more faithfully than anyone.
‪ผมใช้ชีวิตตามหลักคำสอน ‪ของกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ยิ่งกว่าใครๆ ครับ
But after receiving the decree,
‪แต่พอได้รับประกาศิต
I couldn't help but think that I may have committed sins without knowing.
‪ผมก็อดคิดไม่ได้ว่าเคยก่อบาป ‪โดยที่ไม่รู้ตัวหรือเปล่า
The thought tormented me.
‪ผมเป็นทุกข์เหลือเกินครับ
Anyone could die.
‪คนเราตายอยู่แล้วครับ
Everyone dies eventually.
‪ใครๆ ก็ล้วนต้องตายครับ
They could die of an illness or in an accident.
‪อาจจะตายด้วยโรคภัย หรือตายด้วยอุบัติเหตุ
But the fact that I'm bound for Hell…
‪แต่การบอกว่าผมจะตกนรก…
It makes me hate myself so much.
‪มันทำให้ผมเกลียดตัวเองมากครับ
Your baby is proof that I didn't do anything wrong.
‪เด็กคนนี้คือเครื่องพิสูจน์ว่าผมไม่ได้ทำผิด
Your baby proves
‪ผมไม่ได้ทำอะไรผิดทั้งนั้น ‪ให้เด็กเป็นเครื่องพิสูจน์นะครับ
Do I even have a choice?
‪ฉันมีสิทธิ์เลือกด้วยเหรอคะ
It seems that none of us…
‪ดูเหมือนว่าเราทุกคน
has the right to make our own decisions.
‪ต่างเกิดมาโดยไม่มีสิทธิ์เลือกนะคะ
I'm going to upload a video statement about the baby receiving the decree.
‪ก่อนอื่น ฉันจะอัปโหลดวิดีโอ ‪ที่ทารกได้รับประกาศิตก่อนนะคะ
We have to make it reach as many people as possible.
‪เราต้องทำให้คนเห็นมากเท่าที่ทำได้ค่ะ
Oh, I can help you with that.
‪อ้อ ถ้าแบบนั้นผมมีวิธีดีๆ อยู่ครับ
I used to do live streaming online.
‪เมื่อก่อนผมเคยทำไลฟ์สดทางอินเทอร์เน็ตครับ
I quit after receiving the decree,
‪หลังจากได้รับประกาศิตผมก็เลิกทำไป
but many people will watch it if we upload it to my channel.
‪แต่ถ้าอัปโหลดลงบนช่องผมตอนนี้ ‪ก็จะมีคนดูเยอะเลยครับ
Hold on a second.
‪รอเดี๋ยวนะครับ
I still have all the equipment. I'll bring it out.
‪อุปกรณ์ถ่ายคลิปน่าจะยังอยู่ครับ ‪ตรงนี้ไม่มีแฮะ อ้อ
Hello.
‪สวัสดีค่ะ
I'm Min Hyejin and I was formerly a lawyer at Sodo Law Firm.
‪ฉันมินฮเยจิน อดีตเคยเป็นทนาย ‪อยู่ที่สำนักกฎหมายโซโดค่ะ
What I am about to share with you is a video of a newborn baby
‪วันนี้ฉันจะมาเปิดเผยวิดีโอคลิป ‪ทารกที่เพิ่งคลอดไม่กี่วัน
receiving the decree from an angel.
‪ได้รับประกาศิตจากทูตสวรรค์ให้ทุกท่านได้ชมค่ะ
Song Sohyun's baby.
‪ลูกน้อยของซงโซฮยอน
I understand that this video
‪- ฉันเข้าใจว่าผู้ที่รับชมคลิปวิดีโอนี้ ‪- อีกสามวันจากนี้
will confuse many of you.
‪- คงจะสับสนเป็นอย่างมากค่ะ ‪- เวลา 21:30 นาฬิกา…
What could a newborn baby have done to face God's punishment?
‪ทารกที่เพิ่งคลอดไม่กี่วันก่อบาปอะไร ‪ถึงต้องถูกลงทัณฑ์จากพระเจ้าคะ
The baby's demonstration is at 9:30 p.m. tomorrow.
‪ทารกคนนี้จะถูกทำการสาธิต ‪ในวันพรุ่งนี้ เวลา 21:30 น.ค่ะ
We will broadcast the demonstration of this innocent baby live tomorrow.
‪เราจะถ่ายทอดสดช่วงเวลาการสาธิต ‪ของทารกผู้ไร้ความผิดคนนี้ค่ะ
We'll leave it up to you to interpret its meaning.
‪การตีความขึ้นอยู่กับแต่ละท่านเองค่ะ
And I urge the New Truth to stop deluding people
‪และขอให้กลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ ‪หยุดหลอกลวงว่าหายนะอันน่าขนลุกนี้
by calling this catastrophe God's punishment.
‪เป็นการพิพากษาจากพระเจ้าเถอะค่ะ
She's done it.
‪ก่อเรื่องจนได้ สุดท้ายก็ก่อเรื่องจนได้
What do you think we should do?
‪คณะกรรมการของเรามีความเห็นว่าไงครับ
Well,
‪ไม่รู้สิครับ
maybe it's time for us to adopt the concept of original sin.
‪ถึงเวลาที่เราต้องไปอ้างถึง ‪ทฤษฎีบาปกำเนิดแล้วไหมครับ
We can say that humans are born sinners--
‪จะได้บอกว่ามนุษย์เรามีบาปตั้งแต่เกิด…
That is not acceptable!
‪แบบนั้นไม่ได้สิครับ
The New Truth was able to build influence quickly
‪การที่กลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ของเรา ‪ทรงอิทธิพลได้ในเวลาอันสั้นขนาดนี้
because we made people understand why some sinners were bound for Hell.
‪เพราะเราสามารถทำให้เหล่าคนบาป ‪เข้าใจขอบข่ายการตกนรกได้
As soon as we adopt that concept,
‪วินาทีที่เรายอมรับทฤษฎีบาปกำเนิด
people will start to wonder how we are different from Protestants.
‪คนก็จะสงสัยแน่นอนว่า ‪เราต่างจากนิกายโปรเตสแตนต์ตรงไหนครับ
-We'll lose our influence in no time. -Then what? You have a better idea?
‪อิทธิพลเราจะป่นปี้ในพริบตาแน่ครับ
Chairman.
‪ท่านประธานคะ
We still have some time.
‪เอ่อ เรายังพอมีเวลาอยู่นะคะ
How about we claim that the video has been manipulated
‪เราปฏิเสธว่าคลิปวิดีโอนั่นถูกปลอมแปลงไปก่อน
and see how the public responds to it?
‪แล้วรอดูกระแสจากสังคมดีไหมคะ
The demonstration is yet to be held.
‪เพราะการสาธิตยังไม่เกิดขึ้นเลยนี่คะ
What if they really broadcast the baby's demonstration?
‪แล้วถ้าคนพวกนั้น ‪ถ่ายทอดสดการสาธิตของทารกขึ้นมา
What will we say then?
‪เราจะบอกว่าไงล่ะครับ
We should claim that they staged it.
‪เราก็บอกปัดไปว่าการสาธิตถูกกุขึ้นมาด้วยสิคะ
Then people will start to say
‪แบบนั้นคนก็จะเริ่มค้านว่าการสาธิต
You seem eager to find faults in the ideas of others.
‪คุณคะ คุณเอาแต่ขัดคอไม่เลิกตั้งแต่เมื่อกี้แล้ว
We are here to come up with a solution.
‪ตอนนี้เราต้องคิดวิธีแก้ปัญหากันนะคะ
Are you calling me a nitpicker?
‪ผมไปขัดคอคุณตอนไหนครับ
Original sin is the safest option.
‪- บาปกำเนิดปลอดภัยสุดแล้ว ‪- ไม่ต้องแนะนำอะไรแล้ว
-Nothing out of line with our doctrine. -Your suggestion is unreasonable.
‪- อย่าพ่นอะไรออกมาเพ้อเจ้อนะคะ ‪- มันไม่สอดคล้องกับหลักคำสอนของเรา
-Do you even know what original sin is? -Think before you speak!
‪- รู้หรือเปล่าคะว่าบาปกำเนิดคืออะไร ‪- อย่าพูดพล่อยๆ
-I don't even drink apple juice. -Unbelievable.
‪- ฉันไม่ดื่มน้ำแอปเปิลด้วยซ้ำ ‪- พูดเพ้อเจ้อ
-Let's calm down. -Come up with a solution!
‪- ใจเย็นๆ กันก่อน ‪- หาทางออกสิ
-Talk about the facts. -We need a fundamental solution!
‪- แล้วพูดเรื่องนี้ให้มันชัด ‪- เราต้องแก้ต้นตอของปัญหานะคะ
JEONGDAM GROCERY STORE
‪(ร้านขายผลไม้ชองดัม)
Yes.
‪ค่ะ
Okay. One moment.
‪ค่ะ สักครู่นะคะ
Mr. Bae.
‪คุณแบยองแจ
This is one of our members who'll help you and your wife seek asylum.
‪ผู้ดูแลเรื่องการลี้ภัยฝั่งเราค่ะ ‪เขาจะคอยช่วยคุณสองคนลี้ภัย
You won't be able to take a lot of things with you.
‪ถึงจะยังช่วยอะไรไม่ได้มาก
But let them know if there's anything you need.
‪แต่เราจะช่วยให้ถึงที่สุด
They'll try to accommodate as much as possible.
‪ถ้าขาดเหลืออะไรก็บอกได้ตามสบายค่ะ
What about the demonstration?
‪การสาธิตจะเป็นยังไงต่อครับ
We can't go far because it could be dangerous.
‪ถ้าใช้เวลาเดินทางนานจะยิ่งอันตราย
We found a secluded place nearby to minimize collateral damage.
‪เราเลยหาที่ที่ไม่ไกลและเหมาะที่สุด ‪สำหรับหลบสายตาคนให้แล้วค่ะ
Our people will be here soon.
‪อีกไม่นานคนจากฝั่งเราจะมาค่ะ
Hello?
‪ครับ พูดมาเลยครับ
You don't have to be there for the demonstration.
‪คุณไม่จำเป็นต้องอยู่ด้วย ‪ในช่วงที่มีการสาธิตก็ได้ค่ะ
We'll take care of everything.
‪ที่เหลือเราจะจัดการเองค่ะ
At first,
‪ตอนแรก
I couldn't stand all the crying.
‪ฉันไม่อยากฟังเสียงลูกร้องไห้เอาซะเลยค่ะ
It was horrifying.
‪มันน่าสยดสยอง
I didn't know why…
‪เหตุผลคืออะไรก็ไม่รู้…
or what the baby was trying to tell me.
‪แกอยากพูดอะไรกับฉันหรือเปล่า
Babies cry even if they are slightly uncomfortable, right?
‪แค่รู้สึกไม่สบายตัวนิดหน่อย ‪ทารกก็จะร้องไห้ใช่ไหมล่ะคะ
They cry when they are hungry, sleepy, or when it's too cold or too hot.
‪ร้องไห้เพราะหิว เพราะง่วงนอน ‪เพราะหนาว หรือเพราะร้อน
All they can do is cry.
‪เพราะสิ่งที่ลูกทำได้มีแค่การร้องไห้
But now, I see…
‪แต่ว่านะคะ…
that it was…
‪ลูกฉัน…
a cry for help.
‪แกร้องขอชีวิต
That's why the baby was crying.
‪ที่ร้องไห้ก็เพราะเรื่องนั้นค่ะ
Because my baby wants to live.
‪เพราะแกยังอยากมีชีวิตต่อ
The baby was crying for my help.
‪แกร้องไห้เพราะขอให้ช่วย
It's the first time…
‪เป็นครั้งแรกเลยนะคะ
that anyone has wanted my help so badly.
‪ที่มีคนขอความช่วยเหลือจากฉัน ‪อย่างหนักหน่วงแบบนี้
No one has ever told me that I'm their only hope
‪เป็นครั้งแรกที่มีคนบอกฉัน
other than my baby.
‪ว่าต้องเป็นฉันเท่านั้นค่ะ
I'll stay with my baby
‪ฉันจะอยู่กับลูก
until the very end.
‪จนวินาทีสุดท้ายค่ะ
Understood.
‪เข้าใจแล้วค่ะ
I… I need to step out to get some things.
‪เอ่อ ผมจะออกไปซื้อของสักหน่อยครับ
-Is there anything you need? -No, thank you.
‪- ต้องการอะไรไหมครับ ‪- ไม่ค่ะ
All right.
‪ครับ
Chairman Kim Jeongchil is planning on appointing deacons.
‪ประธานคิมจองชิลบอกว่าจะแต่งตั้งคณะนักบวช
How?! What's the basis to decide
‪เดี๋ยวสิ ให้ตายเถอะ
who qualifies and who doesn't to be appointed as a deacon?
‪เอามาตรฐานอะไรมาวัด ‪ในการเป็นคณะนักบวชกันครับ
There is no one else in this world
‪จะมีใครที่ทำตามประสงค์ของพระเจ้า
that is as faithful to God's will as the Arrowhead.
‪ดีเท่าสมาชิกกลุ่มหัวศรของเราอีกล่ะครับ
The Arrowhead won't stop keeping a watchful eye on you! Why?
‪กลุ่มหัวศรของเราจะจับตามองพวกคุณ ‪ไปตลอดครับ ทำไมน่ะเหรอ
To make sure if you remain faithful to God's will or not!
‪ก็เพื่อให้แน่ใจว่าพวกคุณ ‪ทำตามพระประสงค์หรือไม่ไงล่ะ
This is it for today's broadcast.
‪จบการไลฟ์สดสำหรับวันนี้
The Arrowhead!
‪กลุ่มหัวศร กลุ่มหัวศร กลุ่มหัวศร
What is it? Is he on the phone?
‪อะไรครับ ต่อสายอยู่เหรอครับ
Yes, he is.
‪ต่อสายอยู่ค่ะ
Are you really Chairman Kim?
‪ใช่ประธานคิมจองชิลแน่นะครับ
Yes, I am.
‪ครับ แน่สิครับ
And I'm not alone. I have the entire committee with me
‪ตอนนี้ไม่ได้มีแค่ผม ‪แต่คณะกรรมการอยู่ด้วยทั้งหมด
to hear what you have to say.
‪เพื่อจะฟังคุณอีดงอุกครับ
You said Min Hyejin is at your place, correct?
‪เห็นว่าตอนนี้มินฮเยจินอยู่ที่บ้านคุณเหรอครับ
All of them? To what do I owe this honor?
‪อยู่กันครบเชียวเหรอ
Chairman Kim,
‪ประธานคิมจองชิล
listen to me.
‪ฟังผมพูดให้ดีนะครับ
I was a faithful follower of the New Truth
‪ผมเป็นผู้ศรัทธาในกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ ‪อย่างแรงกล้ามาตั้งแต่แรกครับ
even before you became the chairman.
‪ก่อนที่คุณจะเป็นประธานซะอีก
I had been loyal to the New Truth since Chairman Jung founded it.
‪ผมศรัทธาตั้งแต่ประธานจองจินซู ‪ก่อตั้งกลุ่มสัจธรรมใหม่ขึ้นมาครับ
You know,
‪ผมน่ะ
you may think you are better than me,
‪รู้ดียิ่งกว่าพวกคุณที่ฟังผมอยู่ตอนนี้อีก
but I know God's will better than any of you in that room!
‪ผมรู้ประสงค์ของพระเจ้า ‪ดียิ่งกว่าพวกคุณเป็นเท่าตัว
Okay, I see.
‪ครับ อย่างนั้นเหรอครับ
Being a deacon or a committee member
‪ใช่ว่าเราเป็นคณะกรรมการหรือนักบวช
doesn't mean they are closer to God.
‪แล้วจะใกล้ชิดกับพระเจ้า ‪มากกว่าเป็นพิเศษหรอกนะครับ
We are just a group of people
‪พวกเราก็เป็นแค่กลุ่มคน ‪ที่คอยคิดหาวิธีที่จะถ่ายทอดสารจากพระเจ้า
I know that!
‪ผมเองก็รู้โว้ย
Don't patronize me.
‪ไม่ต้องมาสอน
Got it?
‪อย่ามาสอนผม
Please don't get me wrong. I have no intention of patronizing you.
‪เปล่าครับ เปล่าเลย สอนซะที่ไหนกันครับ
Chairman Kim, listen to me carefully
‪ประธานคิมจองชิล ฟังให้ดีล่ะ
and think about what God is trying to say.
‪ว่านี่เป็นพระประสงค์แบบไหนจากพระเจ้า
I received the decree three years ago.
‪ผมได้รับประกาศิตเมื่อสามปีก่อน
I'm bound for Hell.
‪ผมจะตกนรก
But…
‪แต่ว่า…
I have never done anything
‪ผมไม่เคยทำอะไรผิด
that goes against God's will stated in your doctrine.
‪ไปจากประสงค์ของพระเจ้า ‪ในหลักคำสอนที่พวกคุณเขียนไว้เลย
I never told this to Sodo people,
‪เรื่องนี้ผมยังไม่ได้บอกพวกโซโด
but do you know when my demonstration will be held according to the decree?
‪รู้ไหมว่าวันที่ผมจะได้รับการสาธิตคือเมื่อไหร่
Today.
‪วันนี้ไงล่ะ
It's today.
‪วันนี้นี่แหละ
But Min Hyejin and the baby came to my place the day before.
‪แต่มินฮเยจินกับทารกมาอยู่ที่บ้านผมวันก่อน
It turns out my demonstration will be
‪ปรากฏว่าเวลาที่ผมจะถูกสาธิต
five minutes after the baby's.
‪คือห้านาทีหลังจากการสาธิตของทารก
What do you think this means?
‪คิดว่านี่เป็นพระประสงค์แบบไหนล่ะ
What is He trying to say?
‪พระองค์อยากส่งสารอะไร
Well, what you told us is indeed surprising.
‪ครับ เป็นเรื่องที่ประหลาดมาก
-Chairman. -I think…
‪- ท่านประธาน ‪- ผมว่า…
YOU ARE THE MESSIAH
‪(คุณคือเมสสิยาห์)
It's an absolute message.
‪มันคือสารโดยแท้จริง
I think it shows
‪ในความคิดผม
that God sometimes makes mistakes.
‪มันคือข้อพิสูจน์ว่าพระเจ้าก็ทำพลาดได้
And that He is trying to correct them.
‪และนั่นก็เป็นพระประสงค์ที่จะทำให้มันถูกต้องครับ
God somehow made a mistake
‪บางครั้งพระเจ้าก็ทำผิดพลาดครับ
and addressed the decree to a baby.
‪ถึงได้มีการส่งประกาศิตไปให้ทารกไงครับ
What would happen if people find out?
‪ถ้าผู้คนรู้เรื่องนี้จะเกิดอะไรขึ้นล่ะครับ
It'll cause great chaos.
‪ก็คงเกิดความโกลาหลครั้งใหญ่น่ะสิ
Maybe He is trying to cover up His mistake with your demonstration, Mr. Lee.
‪พระองค์จึงพยายามใช้คุณอีดงอุก ‪อำพรางความผิดพลาดนั้นไงครับ
Mr. Lee, you've been chosen to cover up God's mistake,
‪คุณอีดงอุก ‪คือผู้อำพรางความผิดพลาดของพระเจ้า
and He will forever be indebted to you.
‪และเป็นผู้ที่พระเจ้า ‪จะขอบพระทัยมากที่สุดในอนาคต
You are to take on the most important role
‪คุณคือผู้มีบทบาทสูงสุดที่จะทำให้สารจากพระเจ้า
to strengthen His message.
‪ชัดเจนยิ่งขึ้น
Mr. Lee,
‪คุณอีดงอุก
you are the Messiah.
‪คือเมสสิยาห์สินะครับ
I knew it.
‪กะแล้ว
WE NEED TO FIND OUT HIS LOCATION
‪(เราต้องรู้ตำแหน่งครับ)
Mr. Lee. I'm sorry.
‪คุณอีดงอุกครับ
I should call you Messiah from now on.
‪ไม่สิ ตอนนี้ต้องเรียกว่า ‪เมสสิยาห์อีดงอุกแล้วสินะครับ
Where are you right now, sir? We will help you do God's work.
‪ตอนนี้อยู่ที่ไหนครับ ‪เราจะช่วยงานท่านเมสสิยาห์อีดงอุกเองครับ
Help me?
‪ช่วยบ้าบออะไร
Who do you think you are?
‪มีสิทธิ์อะไรจะมาช่วย
God has given me this mission.
‪นี่คืองานที่พระเจ้าฝากฝังผมนะ
God has chosen me to do His work.
‪พระเจ้าทรงเลือกผม
I will never let you deacons steal my thunder ever again!
‪ผมจะไม่ยอมให้นักบวชอย่างพวกคุณ ‪มาพรากเกียรตินี้ไปเด็ดขาด
Listen.
‪ฟังให้ดีล่ะ
I'll kindly leave you a clue,
‪ผมจะทิ้งแค่คำใบ้ไว้เท่านั้น
so you can try all you want to find me.
‪สิ่งที่พวกคุณต้องทำก็ไปหากันเอาเอง
Right, a clue.
‪อ้อ คำใบ้
What the hell?
‪ไอ้เวรเอ๊ย
I even called him the Messiah!
‪ฉันอุตส่าห์เรียกมันว่าเมสสิยาห์
Chairman Kim,
‪ท่านประธาน
we can trace the location of his last call to find him.
‪เราติดตามตำแหน่ง ‪จากการโทรสายสุดท้ายได้ครับ
We can ask an Arrowhead who works at a telecomm company.
‪เราถามพวกหัวศร ‪ที่ทำงานบริษัทโทรคมนาคมได้ครับ
As soon as you get the location,
‪ถ้ารู้ตำแหน่งแล้ว ‪ก็ขนมาให้หมดทั้งพวกหัวศรและตำรวจ
All right, everyone. Get moving! Go!
‪เอาล่ะๆ รีบแยกย้ายครับ เร่งมือเลย
Chairman Kim,
‪ท่านประธาน
Lee Dongwook made his last call near a supermarket in Seongnam.
‪ตำแหน่งการโทรครั้งสุดท้ายของอีดงอุก ‪คือซูเปอร์มาร์เก็ตแถวซองนัมค่ะ
We requested cooperation from the police in the jurisdiction.
‪เราขอความร่วมมือจากตำรวจแล้วค่ะ
I don't care where he was. Go get him right now!
‪จะซองนัมหรืออะไรก็รีบจับมาให้ได้
Go!
‪รีบไป
We located Lee Dongwook.
‪รู้ตำแหน่งอีดงอุกแล้วครับ
Contact the deacons in Seongnam. Get moving!
‪ติดต่อนักบวชแถวซองนัม รีบลงมือ
-Yes, sir.
‪- ครับ
Yes, that's the place.
‪ค่ะ ใช่ที่นั่นค่ะ
Park your car in the underground parking lot.
‪จอดรถไว้ที่ลานจอดใต้ดินแล้วขึ้นมาได้เลยค่ะ
Please hurry.
‪ค่ะ รีบหน่อยนะคะ
They're almost here.
‪ใกล้ถึงแล้วค่ะ
SIWON CLEANING SERVICE
‪(ชีวอน บริการทำความสะอาด)
What's wrong?
‪มีอะไร
One moment.
‪รอเดี๋ยวนะ
-Ms. Min. -Yes.
‪- คุณทนาย ‪- คะ
I'll go check on them.
‪ผมจะออกไปดูนะครับ
Hold on.
‪เดี๋ยวค่ะ
Take it with you.
‪พกไว้ค่ะ
I have to show everyone.
‪ฉันต้องทำให้ผู้คนเห็น
I want to show them something.
‪มีสิ่งที่ฉันอยากให้ทุกคนเห็น
Please seal off this area.
‪ตำรวจล้อมพื้นที่ไว้นะครับ
Yes, sir.
‪ครับ
Search thoroughly.
‪ค้นทุกซอกทุกมุม
Get moving!
‪เร่งมือเร็วเข้า
What happened?
‪เกิดอะไรขึ้น
Hang in there.
‪ตั้งสติไว้นะครับ
Can you hear me?
‪ตั้งสติไว้นะ
The time is near.
‪ตอนนี้เหลือเวลาไม่มากแล้ว
Look at me.
‪มองมาที่ผมสิ ดูสิ
I guess you don't recognize me.
‪สงสัยจะไม่รู้ว่าผมเป็นใครสินะ
I used to be a big shot in the Arrowhead.
‪เมื่อก่อนผมโด่งดังในหมู่กลุ่มหัวศรมากเชียวนะ
Why…
‪ทำไม…
Why are you suddenly doing this?
‪ทำไมจู่ๆ ถึงทำแบบนี้
You received the decree too.
‪คุณเองก็ได้รับประกาศิตนี่
You're right.
‪ถูกต้อง
I will be subjected to the demonstration
‪ผมคือคนที่จะถูกสาธิต
five minutes after your baby.
‪หลังจากลูกคุณห้านาที
I'm the one to cover up God's mistake.
‪ผมคือคนที่จะอำพราง ‪ความผิดพลาดของพระเจ้า
Would you like to hear what my plan is?
‪แผนของผมคืออะไรรู้ไหม ฟังนะ
Firstly, I'm going to kill you here
‪อย่างแรก ผมจะฆ่าคุณที่นี่
and kill your wife and Min Hyejin upstairs.
‪แล้วก็ขึ้นไปฆ่าภรรยาคุณ และฆ่ามินฮเยจินซะ
Then your baby's demonstration will be in my room.
‪หลังจากนั้นผมก็จะให้ลูกคุณ ‪ถูกทำการสาธิตในห้องผม
Within five minutes, I will get rid of the body
‪ภายในห้านาทีนั้น ผมจะเก็บกวาดร่างของเด็ก
and be subjected to the demonstration.
‪แล้วผมก็จะรับการสาธิตที่ห้องนั้นด้วย
Then people won't be sure who was subjected to the demonstration
‪พอแบบนั้นคนก็จะสับสนว่าใครถูกสาธิตกันแน่ ‪และเกิดอะไรขึ้นกับเด็ก
or what happened to the baby.
‪สับสนไปหมดซะทุกเรื่อง
They will be confused.
‪ทุกคนจะสับสนแน่
Come to think of it, I didn't know God could be so damn despicable.
‪แต่จะว่าไปนะ พระเจ้านี่ช่างเหลี่ยมจัดซะจริง
How could He make a mistake?
‪ตัวเองทำพลาด
How?
‪ฮะ
And He's chosen me to cover up His mistake?
‪แล้วก็เลือกผมเพื่อจะปกปิดความผิดพลาดนั้น
Wait.
‪เดี๋ยวก่อน
I don't understand what you're saying.
‪ผมไม่เข้าใจว่าคุณพูดเรื่องอะไร
But please calm down.
‪แต่ใจเย็นๆ ก่อน
Come to your senses.
‪แล้วตั้งสติเถอะนะครับ
What do you mean?
‪สติเหรอ
My mind has never been clearer.
‪ตั้งแต่เกิดมา ‪ผมไม่เคยสติแจ่มชัดขนาดนี้เลยนะ
I can see clearly why I was born and why I am dying.
‪ผมรู้ชัดเจนว่าตัวเองเกิดมาทำไม ‪และทำไมถึงตาย
Not many people get to understand that.
‪คิดว่าจะมีสักกี่คนบนโลกที่รู้เรื่องนี้
I am the one…
‪ตอนนี้…
who is closest to God.
‪ผมคือคนที่ใกล้ชิดกับพระเจ้าที่สุด
Sohyun!
‪โซฮยอน
Sohyun, run!
‪โซฮยอน หนีไป
Ms. Min!
‪คุณทนาย
Everyone.
‪ทุกคนคะ
There is something…
‪ฉันมีสิ่งหนึ่ง…
I need to show you all.
‪ที่อยากจะให้ทุกคนเห็นค่ะ
This is my baby…
‪เด็กคนนี้…
who is about to be subjected to
‪เป็นเป้าหมายที่จะถูกทำการสาธิต
the demonstration.
‪ในอีกไม่นานค่ะ
A baby?
‪ทารกเนี่ยนะ
Please stay and witness the moment.
‪ช่วยเป็นสักขีพยานทีนะคะ
-That's not right. -How could a baby…
‪- ไม่ถูกต้องไหม ‪- ทารกจะทำบาปอะไรได้
What?
‪โอ๊ะ
-They've been located. -Deacon Yuji.
‪- ทราบตำแหน่งแล้วครับ ‪- ท่านนักบวช
Please check this out.
‪ดูนี่หน่อยครับ
This is near here.
‪อยู่ใกล้ๆ นี่เองครับ
BABY SUBJECT, REAL-TIME BABY DEMONSTRATION, INFANT
‪(#การสาธิตทารก #สถานการณ์เรียลไทม์ ‪#ทารกได้ประกาศิต #การสาธิตทารกแรกเกิด)
-Head there now. -Get moving!
‪- รีบแยกย้ายครับ ‪- รีบแยกย้าย
Poor baby…
‪หนูน้อยน่าสงสาร…
My baby…
‪ลูกจ๋า
I will…
‪แม่คนนี้…
I will be with you until the end.
‪จะอยู่ข้างๆ ลูกจนวินาทีสุดท้ายเองนะ
How much farther?
‪อีกไกลแค่ไหน
Almost there.
‪ใกล้ถึงแล้วครับ
I don't have time for this!
‪บอกว่าไม่มีเวลาแล้ว ไม่มีเวลา
Let go of me! Let go! Damn it!
‪ปล่อย ปล่อยสิวะ เวรเอ๊ย
You're a mere mortal!
‪แกมันก็แค่มนุษย์
Die!
‪ตาย ตายซะ
Sohyun!
‪โซฮยอน
It's going to be okay.
‪ไม่เป็นไรนะ
No.
‪ไม่นะ
What the hell?
‪นี่มันอะไรกัน
You bastard.
‪ไอ้ชั่ว
What the hell are you trying to tell me, you asshole?
‪แกอยากบอกอะไรฉันกันแน่วะ ไอ้เวร
Carry on?
‪ทำตามแผนเหรอ
Okay, I'll carry on with the plan.
‪อ๋อ ทำตามแผน
Wait.
‪เดี๋ยวก่อน
Oh, my goodness.
‪ห่มไว้นะ
Get her!
‪จับตัวไว้
Get out of the way!
‪หลีกไป
Step aside!
‪ออกมา
Move!
‪ออกมาสิ
Get out of the way now!
‪หลีกไป
-Get out of the way! -Move!
‪- ไปให้พ้น ‪- ไปสิ
You are going against God's will.
‪พวกคุณกำลังขัดขืนประสงค์ของพระเจ้าอยู่
Get out of the way now!
‪รีบหลีกไปเดี๋ยวนี้
Get out of the way!
‪หลีกไป หลีกไปสิ ไป
Stop it!
‪พอได้แล้ว
You pathetic crooks.
‪ไอ้พวกลวงโลก
What did you say?
‪ว่าไงนะ
Enough is enough.
‪พอได้แล้ว
You are all liars.
‪พวกขี้โกหก
What did you just call me?
‪ว่าไงนะ
What did you say?
‪พูดอะไรออกมา
Hey.
‪นี่
You disregard God's principles
‪โทษฐานที่ขัดขืนหลักการของพระเจ้า
and go against God's will.
‪โทษฐานที่เพิกเฉยพระประสงค์ของพระองค์
Who are you to call me a crook?
‪กล้าดียังไงมาเรียกฉันว่าคนลวงโลก
How dare you!
‪กล้าดียังไง
What are you still doing here? Go get that bitch. Damn it.
‪มัวทำอะไรอยู่ รีบตามไปจับนังนั่นสิ เวรเอ๊ย
Deacon Yuji.
‪นักบวชยูจี
You are under arrest for battery.
‪คุณถูกจับกุมฐานใช้ความรุนแรงซึ่งหน้าครับ
You have the right to remain silent.
‪คุณมีสิทธิ์ที่จะไม่พูด
-You have the right to an attorney. -What are you doing?
‪- และมีสิทธิ์แต่งตั้งทนาย ‪- พูดอะไรน่ะ
Come on.
‪มา
What the hell are you saying?
‪เห่าอะไรออกมา
Do you have any idea what you're doing right now?
‪พวกแกรู้ไหมว่ากำลังทำอะไรอยู่
Do you know what it means if God acts without logic?
‪รู้ไหมว่าการที่พระเจ้าไม่มีหลักการเลย ‪มันหมายถึงอะไร
It means the end of the world.
‪อวสานโลกไงล่ะ
More sinners will ruin the world.
‪ต่อไปจะมีคนบาปอีกมากที่ทำตัวกร่าง
The victims of those sinners will hold you responsible for everything.
‪เหยื่อของคนบาปพวกนั้นจะโกรธแค้นพวกแก
You are the ones who are helping the sinners to sin.
‪พวกแกคือคนที่ยุยงให้คนบาปพวกนั้นก่อบาปขึ้นมา
Shame on you.
‪ละอายใจซะเถอะ
Shame on you!
‪หัดละอายใจซะบ้าง
You disregard God's principles and go against God's will.
‪โทษฐานที่ไม่รู้หลักการของพระเจ้า ‪และเมินเฉยพระประสงค์ของพระองค์
-Who are you to… -Let's head back.
‪- พวกแก… ‪- กลับเถอะ
Please take the main road and drive as far away as possible.
‪ออกไปทางถนนเส้นหลักแล้วไปให้ไกลที่สุดค่ะ
The main road is straight ahead.
‪ถนนเส้นหลักต้องขับตรงไปนะคะ
The police set up a checkpoint on that street.
‪ถ้าตรงไปจะเจอด่านตำรวจน่ะสิครับ
I saw it on my way here,
‪เมื่อกี้ขามาผมเห็นครับ
Ms. Min Hyejin.
‪คุณทนายมินฮเยจิน
I'll take a different route to the main road.
‪ถ้าจะขึ้นถนนเส้นหลักต้องไปทางนั้นครับ
It's safer.
‪แบบนั้นถึงจะปลอดภัยครับ
I don't know much about God,
‪ผมไม่รู้หรอกว่าพระเจ้าเป็นคนยังไง ‪แล้วก็ไม่สนด้วยครับ
One thing I know for sure
‪สิ่งหนึ่งที่ผมรู้ชัดเจน
is that this world belongs to us.
‪คือที่นี่เป็นโลกของมนุษย์ครับ
We should settle our own affairs.
‪โลกของมนุษย์ มนุษย์ก็ต้องจัดการกันเองสิครับ
Don't you agree, Ms. Min?
‪เห็นด้วยไหมครับ คุณทนาย